Guide to the Arab Political Posters Collection, 1970s RL.11680
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Arab political posters collection
1970s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11680
3 Linear Feet 14 posters in 1 oversize folder
Collection of assorted posters in Arabic commemorating revolutionary and political movements in Yemen, Oman, Palestine, and the Middle East.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Arab Political Posters were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2018.
Collection Overview
14 posters in Arabic addressing a variety of political and revolutionary movements and events.
Arab-Israeli conflict; Arab countries -- Study and teaching; Refugees, Arab; Palestine -- Politics and government -- 1948-; Israel -- Foreign relations -- Palestine; Oman; Yemen (Republic); Human Rights -- Palestine
- Poster commemorating the 7th anniversary of the founding of al-`Asifah, approximately 1972-1974 (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0001)
  Scope and Contents
  Rome (Italy). Unione Generale Studenti Palestinesi Italia. In Italian and some Arabic. The poster commemorates the founding of the armed wing of al-Fatah, al-`Asifah.
- Poster commemorating the 2nd anniversary of the Battle of Karameh, approximately 1970-1972 (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0002)
  France: General Union of Palestinian Students (GUPS). In French with a declaration: "Une grande victoire du peuple Palestinien."
- Poster commemorating 15 May 1948, undated (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0003)
  France: General Union of Palestinian Students (GUPS). In French: Journee de la lutte Palestinienne. In Arabic: Yawm al-niḍāl al-Filasṭīnī (The day of the Palestinian struggle).
- Poster commemorating the 5th anniversary of the Democratic Front for the Liberation of Palestine, 1974 Feb. (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0004)
- Poster commemorating the 5th anniversary of the Battle of Karameh, undated (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0005)
  France: Comité permanent d'action pour la Palestine. In French.
- Poster commemorating Justice for Christian Riss, undated (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0006)
  Imprimerie Abexpress, Paris. In French and Arabic.
- Chinese political poster in support of Palestine, undated (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0007)
  Shanghai: Shanghai People's Publishing House. In Chinese, English, and French.
- Poster of the People's Democratic Front of Palestine, undated (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0008)
  Italy. In Italian, French and English. This poster calls for the unity of those against Imperialism and Zionism.
- Poster of armed soldier of al-`Asifah, undated (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0009)
  Palestine: Official poster of Fatah and the armed wing, al-`Asifah. In Arabic. Commemorates the founding of the Palestinian revolution.
- Poster commemorating the Massacre at Sabra and Chatila, undated (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0010)
  Cuba: Organization of Solidarity with the People of Asia, Africa and Latin America (OSPAAAL). In Spanish, French and English. The poster is two-sided; one side with child's face and the other side with notes about the massacre in Sabra and Chatila orchestrated by Israel on the Palestinian refugee camp.
- Poster for the Yemen Revolutionary Resistance Organization (ORYR), approximately 1970-1975 (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0011)
  Yemen: Yemen Revolutionary Resistance Organization (ORYR). In Arabic. The poster details some of the prominent members of ORYR.
- Poster for the Yemen Revolutionary Resistance Organization (ORYR) suggesting President Saleh is similar to Hitler and Stalin, approximately 1970-1976 (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0012)
  Yemen: Yemen Revolutionary Resistance Organization (ORYR). In Arabic. Three figures are portrayed one of each former Yemeni President Saleh, Adolf Hitler and Joseph Stalin. The poster notes that fascism is everywhere.
- Poster for the People's Revolution in Oman, approximately 1970-1974 (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0013)
  Paris: Paris cedex Imp. IPCC Sup. a El Jabha. In Arabic and French. Comité de soutien à la révolution en Oman.
- Poster for the People's Revolution in Oman, approximately 1970-1974 (Folder 1, Item RL-11680-P-0014)
  Paris: Paris cedex Imp. IPCC Sup. a El Jabha. In Arabic and French. Poster produced for Comité de soutien à la révolution en Oman. Idential image as previous poster RL-11680-P-0013. However, this poster is in yellow and purple and includes the details on a meeting of the committee. Included at the meeting are the musical groups of Chorale de la Penninsule Arabique along with Mohamed Hamam, the Groupe Musical Arabe and Chorale de l'Union des Etudiants Iraniens en France. Taking place at 2pm on 14 March.